Guide to the Undergraduate Publications Board records, 1911-2002 UA.31.01.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Undergraduate Publications Board records
1911-2002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Undergraduate Publications Board
UA.31.01.0001
6 Linear Feet 9 boxes
Since 1924, the Undergraduate Publications Board, commonly referred to as the Pub Board or UPB, has overseen the production of each of the university's recognized publications (with the exception of The Chronicle and Towerview). The UPB also runs the Blackburn Literary Festival. The collection contains correspondence, memoranda, UPB constitution and bylaws, income reports, clippings, oral histories, and other materials relating to the daily operations of the Undergraduate Publications Board and individual publications produced by the Undergraduate Publications Board. Materials in the collection date from circa 1911-2002.
Access Restrictions
Use of audiotapes and videotapes from this collection requires the creation of reference copies. Reference copies for some materials may have been made, and if a reference copy exists, it is noted in this finding aid. To arrange for the creation of reference copies of other items, please contact University Archives staff. Although these recordings are now stored in a stable environment, their condition and playback quality is unknown.
Provenance
The Undergraduate Publications Board records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1973-2005, 2015.
Historical Note
Since 1924, the Undergraduate Publications Board, commonly referred to as the Pub Board or UPB, has overseen the production of each of the university's recognized publications (with the exception of The Chronicle and Towerview). The Board also approves and supports emerging publications, known as Independents, runs the Blackburn Literary Festival, and administers the John Spencer Bassett Fund. Its continuing mission is to provide diverse forums in which students can engage their creative, intellectual, political and literary faculties.
Currently (2007), the UPB oversees the production of eleven publications: The Archive; Blind Spot; Carpe Noctem; The Chanticleer; Duke Blue; Erudito; Latent Image; Matter Magazine; Vertices; Passport Magazine; and Woman's Handbook. A sampling of other titles produced during the UPB's history include: Tobacco Road; Prometheus Black; Missing Link, Jabberwocky; and Teacher-Course Evaluation Book. For a list of Undergraduate Publications Board publications held by the University Archives see the related material section below.
Source: Undergraduate Publications Board homepage http://www.duke-union.org/About_UPB [Viewed 2016]
Collection Overview
The collection contains correspondence, memoranda, Undergraduate Publications Board (UPB) constitution and bylaws, income reports, clippings, oral histories, and other materials relating to the daily operations of the UPB and individual publications produced by the UPB. Topics of interest include: editorships and selection of editors; appointments to the Publications Board; the proposed separation of Publications Board from ASDU; Handbook for Board Members; editorial guides; guidelines for use of the J.S. Bassett Fund; history of the "sinking fund;" history of the Chanticleer naming; and items relating to the Blackburn Literary Festival, including correspondence with visiting poets and authors.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is divided into two large groups: Series 1, the records of the Undergraduate Publications Board, and Series 2, records of the individual publications.
Related Material
ASDU's student guide to Duke [serial].
University Archives. Duke University.
Chanticleer photograph collection, circa 1998-2003.
University Archives. Duke University.
Duke women's handbook [serial].
University Archives. Duke University.
Eruditio [serial].
University Archives. Duke University.
Ethos, [serial].
University Archives. Duke University.
The forum: a Duke humanities journal [serial].
University Archives. Duke University.
Matter, [serial].
University Archives. Duke University.
Modern Crisis, [serial].
University Archives. Duke University.
Museo, [serial].
University Archives. Duke University.
Pyrofax. 1970.
University Archives. Duke University.
Swing [serial], 1990-1992.
University Archives. Duke University.
Thread, 2003-2005.
University Archives. Duke University.
Undergraduate Publications Board Reference Collection, 1927-[ongoing].
University Archives. Duke University.
Conditions Governing Access
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Conditions Governing Access
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
College prose, American -- North Carolina -- Durham; College publications; College student newspapers and periodicals -- North Carolina -- Durham; College students -- North Carolina -- Durham; College students' writings, American; Students' writings; Duke University Publications Board; Duke University. Undergraduate Publications Board
- Undergraduate Publications Board, 1935-2002, 4 Boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Series includes correspondence, memoranda, UPB constitution and bylaws, reports, clippings, black and white photographs of visiting authors, individual publications records, and other materials relating to the daily operations of the Undergraduate Publications Board. The series is divided into four subseries: administrative records, publications files, subject files, and files relating to the Blackburn Literary Festival.
  - 1.1. Administrative records, 1935-1993, bulk 1970-1985
    - Applications for Editorship, 1977-1981 RESTRICTED (Box 1)
    - Applications for Editorship, 1984-1985 RESTRICTED (Box 1)
    - Applications for Editorship, 1985-1986 RESTRICTED (Box 1)
    - Applications for Editorship, 1987-RESTRICTED (Box 1)
    - Audit Reports, 1976- (Box 1)
    - Bassett Committee, 1963-1992(2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Chairman's Report, (Jim Young), 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, 1935- (Box 1)
    - Contracts, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1992(3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Editor's Agreements, 1979- (Box 1)
    - Editor's Reports, 1978-1985 (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Endowment Fund, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Finances and Budgets, 1976-1990(3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Finance Committee, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Handbook for Board Members, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Membership Lists, 1976-1993 (Box 1)
    - Minutes - Executive Committee Meeting, 1977, 1980, 1983 (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Minutes and Agendas, 1961; 1971-1993(8 folders) (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Papers from the administration of Zac Issac, Chairman, 1976-1977 (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Publications Board Study Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - Publications Board Study Committee, Report, [1971] (Box 1)
    - Report, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Reports, 1980; 1992 (Box 1)
  - 1.2. Publications files, 1937-1997
    - Archive, 1937-1938 (Box 2)
    - Blind Spot, 1991, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Chanticleer, 1976 (Box 2)
    - The Chronicle, 1962-1981 (Box 2)
    - Duke Blue, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Duke Guide, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Duke Humanities Review, 1980 (Box 2)
    - Jabberwock y, 1986, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Erudito, 1995-1997 (Box 2)
    - Latent Image, 1976, 1994-1996 (Box 2)
    - Missing Link, 1984, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Open Forum, 1994, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Pravda, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
    - Prometheus Black, 1991-1992, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Salty Observer, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Talking Drum, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Teacher-Course Evaluation Book, 1976, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Tobacco Road, 1978-1996 (Box 2)
    - Vertices, 1984, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Women's Handbook, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - 1.3. Subject files, 1959-1997
    - Ad Hoc Committee on the Duke Undergraduate Media - Report, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Ad Hoc Salary Committee, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Associated Collegiate Press Convention, New Orleans, October 27-29, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Associated Collegiate Press Convention, Houston, Texas, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Bassett Commemoration, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Blackburn Literary Festival, 1978-1997 (Box 3)
    - Booklet by Janet Holmes -- The Structure and Function of the Publications Board, circa 1977, 1978 (2 copies) (Box 3)
    - Clippings - General, 1976- (Box 3)
    - Composition Shop, [c. 1976-1977] (Box 3)
    - Ethics Code (Box 3)
    - Funding - ASDU, 1971-1990 (Box 3)
    - Proposal to House Publications in East Campus Center, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Questionnaires, 1971; 1977 (Box 3)
    - Rappaport Studio, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Salary Study Committee - Report, 1959 (Box 3)
    - Seminar: Libel and Student Media, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Student Guide to Duke, 1991 (Box 3)
    - VDT Machine, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - 1.4. Blackburn Literary Festival, 1998-2002
    - Blackburn Literary Festival, 1998-2001; 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Blackburn Literary Festival, 1999-2000; 1 folders (Box 9)
    - Blackburn Literary Festival, 1999-2000; 1 folders (Box 9)
    - The Big Book of Publications Board, 2000-2002; 2 folders (Box 9)
- Individual Publications records, 1911-1994, 4 boxes
  Series contains the records of individual publications produced by the Undergraduate Publications Board. The series is divided into four subseries: Chanticleer; Missing Link; Prometheus Black; and Tobacco Road.
  - 2.1 Chanticleer, 1911-1981.
    The Chanticleer is Duke's annual student-produced yearbook. The first issue was published in 1912.
    Subseries include papers, clippings, financial statements, awards, correspondence concerning yearbook production, and other printed matter concerning the operations of the Chanticleer. Particular items include an account book, 1911-1912, of A.S. Brower (business manager), and articles "The Naming of the Chanticleer," by A.C. Jordon (1973) and "In Defense of the Yearbook," by Kerry Wilson (1976).
    - Chanticleer 1921, 1913, 1921 (includes the cover from the 1913 Chanticleer) (Box 4)
    - Account Book, 1921 (Box 4)
    - Financial Statements, 1922 (Box 4)
    - Business Manager (A.S. Brower) Ledger, 1911-1912 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous [Clippings, correspondence, history of the name Chanticleer], 1935-1981 (Box 4)
  - 2.2: Missing Link, 1983-1989.
    The Missing Link is a twice monthly Duke publication designed to promote student involvement in the intellectual and cultural activities around Duke and Durham. It was first published in 1983.
    Subseries includes correspondence, minutes, forms, memos, notes, income statements, and other materials concerning the Missing Link's operations and the activities of the Publications Board. The Missing Link files include financial records, procedural documents, including assignment sheets and notices to contributors, flyers and advertising information, materials concerning fund raising campaigns, reviews of the newspaper by members of the Pub Board, and a file concerning a 1987 controversy over the publications's budget allocation.
    - Ad Ideas, Contracts, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Advertising Brochures (Box 5)
    - ASDU debate concerning SOC budget allocations for Missing Link, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Board [Publications] Review of Missing Link issues, 1986, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Budget Ideas, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
    - Bureaucracy, 1989, undated (Box 5)
    - Dead Accounts, undated (Box 5)
    - Editorship Applications (Box 5)
    - Fund Raising, 1986 (Box 5)
    - The Missing Link, vol. I (1983-1984) (Box 5)
    - The Missing Link, vol. II (1984-1985) (Box 5)
    - The Missing Link, vol. III (1985-1986) (Box 5)
    - The Missing Link, vol. IV (1986-1987) (Box 5)
    - Missing Link Business, 1985-1986 (includes financial and income statements) (Box 5)
    - Missing Link, General, 1986-1989 (Box 5)
    - Notes, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Pub Board - Ad Hoc Committee on Undergraduate Publications Board Computer Committee, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Publications Boards, Minutes and Agendas, undated, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
    - Publicity (Box 5)
  - 2.3. Prometheus Black records, 1976-1994
    Prometheus Black "publishes creative writing and artwork with a focus on the excellence of the African Americans in the Duke community." (Prometheus Black website, 2005)
    Subseries contains submissions, correspondence, flyers, membership lists, and other records of Prometheus Black. Records also include a few examples of related publications from other institutions.
    - Administrative materials (correspondence, phone lists, etc.), Summer 1994 (Box 6)
    - AfricaNews, March 8-21, 1993 vol. 38, no. 2-3 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976-1988 (Box 6)
    - Original Submissions, 1976, 1994 (Box 6)
  - 2.4. Tobacco Road, 1974-1993.
    Tobacco Road was an experimental magazine funded by the Undergraduate Publications Board. The format was one of general features. It was first published in 1978. The last issue printed was Spring 2003.
    The subseries includes correspondence, announcements, memoranda, clippings, applications, questionnaires, and seventeen student interviews on standard-size audiocassettes. Each student interviewed released the contents of the tape for archival use. The collection ranges in date from 1974-1993.
    - Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 7)
    - Information, 1986-1987 (Box 7)
    - Middle East Survey, undated (Box 7)
    - Advertising, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - Applications and Questionnaires, 1979-1980 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1982 (Box 7)
    - Notes from Staff Meetings, 1977-1978 (Box 7)
    - Copy (Used) - Second Issue, January 22, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Expenses and Press Releases, 1982-1989 (Box 7)
    - Announcements and Memoranda, 1974-1993 (Box 7)
    - Printing Specifications for Competitive Bidding, 1979 (Box 7)
    - Magazine Archives (Plans, Epistles, etc.), undated (Box 7)
    - Newspaper Coverage, 1978, undated (Box 7)
    - William Chafe, March 1983 (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0001)
      Conditions Governing Access
      A use copy of this audio recording must be made before access can be granted.
    - John Austin, March 27, 1983 (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0002)
    - Rita Chambers, March 31, 1983 (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0003)
    - Mark Marshall, April 6, 1983 (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0004)
    - Mary Anne Widmann, April 6, 1983 (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0005)
    - Liz Aldridge, undated (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0006)
    - Monica Breckenridge, undated (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0007, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0008)
    - Robert Bright, undated (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0009)
    - Walter Christman, undated (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0010)
    - Matt Doyle, undated (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0011)
    - Chip Henderson, Bob Hall, undated (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0012)
    - Chip Ireland, undated (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0013)
    - Sam Jones, undated (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0014)
    - Ku Su Nyu, undated (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0015)
    - Joe Scoder, undated (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0016)
    - Patrick Slater, undated (Box 8, Audio-cassette UA31010001-CS-0017)